Guide to the Hermann Herrey papers, ca. 1939-1971.
Herrey, Hermann papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hermann Herrey papers, ca.1939-1971
3476
Hermann Herrey, 1904-1968
16.5 cubic ft.
Drawings, paintings, plans and photographs (including glass plate negatives), planning projects, stage designs, industrial designs, furniture, inventions, correspondence, biographical material, lecture notes, talks, reports, and manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Drawings, paintings, plans and photographs (including glass plate negatives) of architectural work, planning projects, stage designs, industrial designs, furniture and inventions. Also includes correspondence, biographical material, lecture notes, talks and reports; writings in city and regional planning, economic development, architecture, theater and related fields. Also, manuscript of a novel written by Herrey in the 1930s; and a play written under the pseudonym of Gilbert Tanner, ca.1960.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
A native of Vienna, Hermann Herrey was educated in Vienna and Berlin, and worked as a stage designer in Germany and England before coming to the United States in 1940, at the invitation of Walter Gropius. Herrey adapted and rewrote modern and classical plays and translated other plays into English and German; designed stage sets and costumes; and lectured at colleges and universities, including Harvard University, McGill University, Yale University, Queens College and The American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Drawings, paintings, plans and photographs (including glass plate negatives) of architectural work, planning projects, stage designs, industrial designs, furniture and inventions. Also includes correspondence, biographical material, lecture notes, talks and reports; writings in city and regional planning, economic development, architecture, theater and related fields. Also, manuscript of a novel written by Herrey in the 1930s; and a play written under the pseudonym of Gilbert Tanner, ca.1960.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Herrey, Hermann, 1904-1968.; Tanner, Gilbert.
Subjects:
Architectural design.; Classical drama.; Costume design.; Drama--20th century.; Furniture design.; Design, Industrial.; Playwriting.; Theater.; City planning.; Regional planning.; Stage adaptations.; Theaters--Stage-setting and scenery.; Architects.; City planners.; Theatrical producers and directors.
Form and Genre Terms:
Drawings.; Lecture notes.; Paintings.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Publications containing articles by or about H.H. (publications are American, German, English, and French) from 1940s and 1950s, 1940-1950s (Box 1)
- Publications as above, 1 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of clippings from English papers and periodicals concerning architecture and planning 1939 (not works of H.H.), 2 (Box 2)
- Black looseleaf volume of clippings and articles in German concerning plays, 1958, 3 (Box 2)
- Black looseleaf volume containing photographs of scenes from plays, stage sets, etc., 4 (Box 10)
- Folders relating to Guggenheim Foundation Award and H.H. application for same, 1943, 1950, 1 (Box 3)
- Folders relating to traffic, roads, etc., 2 (Box 3)
- Folders relating to Self-Service Garage, 1947, 3 (Box 3)
- Folders relating to investigations on Stream of Movements, 1941, 4 (Box 3)
- Folders relating to Exhibit plans of road communications, 1947-1949, 5 (Box 3)
- Folder - correspondence and article for Atlantic Monthly, 1945, 6 (Box 3)
- Folder - miscellaneous correspondence, 1940s and 1950s, 7 (Box 3)
- Folder - Harvard University correspondence, 1942, 8 (Box 3)
- Photograph album of set design by H.H., 9 (Box 3)
- Work file - Mrs. Alma Morgenthau 1, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Work file - Mrs. Alma Morgenthau 2, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Projects - Traffic etc., London, 1941-1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Projects - INVESTIGATION III - Analysis of Activities and Opportunities (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Projects - Road Traffic and Terminals Exhibition, 1948-1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Projects - Defense Traffic Problem, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Projects - The "Road" Exhibition, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Projects - The "Road" Exhibition, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Projects - Traffic, correspondence, 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Investigation of the Procedure of the Stream of Movements at Intersections (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Projects - Road Communication, 1939-1941 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Philosophical Society - abstract About the Significance of Community for Modern Planning, Aug. 25, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Report - A Scientific Approach Towards the Problems of Communication Planning, Ja. 4, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Harvard University - correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Exhibition Projects on Road Communications and Settlements (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Research and Exhibition Project- Stream of Movements, Road Systems, Settlements, June, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Project - Traffic Exhibit, U.S.A. correspondence, 1939-1942 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Atlantic Monthly - correspondence (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Correspondence:
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - Misc. (Box 4a, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - A (Box 4a, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - B (Box 4a, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - C (Box 4a, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - D (Box 4a, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - E (Box 4a, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - F (Box 4a, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - G (Box 4a, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - H (Box 4a, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - I-J (Box 4a, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - K (Box 4a, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - L (Box 4a, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - M (Box 4a, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - O (Box 4a, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - P (Box 4a, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - R (Box 4a, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - S (Box 4a, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - Sch (Box 4a, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - T (Box 4a, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - W (Box 4a, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence- Letterbook 1 - X-Z (Box 4a, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Deutsche (Box 4a, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Berliner Apartment (Box 4a, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook - File 1 (Box 4a, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook File 2 (Box 4a, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook File 3 (Box 4a, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook current File Misc. 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File A-J 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File A-J 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File A-J 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence -Letterbook Current File - C 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File D 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 32)
  - Correnpondence - Letterbook Current File E 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File F 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File G 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File H 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File I-J 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File K 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File L 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File M 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File N 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File P-Q 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File R 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File S 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File T 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File U 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File V 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File W 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Current File Y-Z 1965 (Box 4a, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre Misc. (Box 4b, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre A (Box 4b, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre B (Box 4b, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre C (Box 4b, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre D (Box 4b, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre E (Box 4b, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre F (Box 4b, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre G (Box 4b, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre H (Box 4b, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre I-J (Box 4b, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre K (Box 4b, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre L (Box 4b, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre M (Box 4b, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre N (Box 4b, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre P-Q (Box 4b, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre R (Box 4b, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre S (Box 4b, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre Sch (Box 4b, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre St. (Box 4b, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre T (Box 4b, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre V (Box 4b, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre W (Box 4b, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Theatre X-Z (Box 4b, Folder 23)
  - Correnpondence - Letterbook Current File E 1965 (Box 4b, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Employment Prospects 1, 1942-1943 (Box 4b, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Employment Prospects 2, 1942-1943 (Box 4b, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Employment Prospects 3, 1942-1943 (Box 4b, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Employment Prospects 4, 1942-1943 (Box 4b, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook Employment Prospects 5, 1942-1943 (Box 4b, Folder 29)
  - Draft - On Public Support for the Arts (Box 4b, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - Letterbook International Resources Development Conference, American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia (Box 4b, Folder 31)
  - Correspondene General Folder 1-1, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-2, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-3, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-4, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-5, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-6, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-7, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-8, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-9, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-10, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-11, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence General Folder 1-12, 1950-1952 (Box 4b, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence Mrs. Erna Herrey 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Mrs. Erna Herrey 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Mrs. Erna Herrey 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Mrs. Erna Herrey 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Mrs. Erna Herrey 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - German Lecture on "German Theatre", March 16,1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Dr. Shapely, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence United Scenic Artists 1942 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence United Scenic Artists 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence United Scenic Artists 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- "Mss. of a novel written in the early thirties. Play under pseudonym of Gilbert Tanner based on the novel written about 1960 .", 1 (Box 5)
- Material concerning the article, 2 (Box 5)
- Personal notebook of addresses, cards, and notes, etc., 3 (Box 5)
- German lecture on "German Theatre," 1963, 4 (Box 5)
- State Street Redeveloper's Proposal, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Annotated Script "N" or "This is Our World" Gilbert Tanner, in English and German (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Gilbert Tanner "N" Schauspiel (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Theatre Clippings and Photographs "Macbeth" 1960 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Theatre Clippings "Macbeth" 1960 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Set Design Graphics "Faust" 1932 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- New York Proposal Part 1 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- New York Proposal Part 2 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- New York Project 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- New York Project 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Hand Written Research Notes 1935 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Research Notes (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Theatre Research Notes (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Drawings and Plans Misc. (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Work Files (Box 6a)
  - Workfile (Box 6a, Folder 1)
  - Project File - Remodeling work for House of Mr. and Mrs. Albert Stahl, 184-27, Hanley Road, Jamaica, Queens, NY, December 1, 1944 (Box 6a, Folder 2)
  - Project File - New residence Old Westbury L.I., December 1, 1944 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
  - Project File - Remodeling work for Mr. William Hicks, Tanglewood Lane, Sea Cliff, Long Island 1951, November 1, 1943 (Box 6a, Folder 4)
  - Projects File - Drafts for Scheme for a Manhattan Interior Highway and Parking Belt, and The Origins of Slums (Box 6a, Folder 5)
  - Projects Files - Furniture Designs (Box 6a, Folder 6)
  - Project File - Remodeling Work for House of Mrs. Diane Wallis, 11 East 67th Street, NY, NY (Box 6a, Folder 7)
  - Projects Files - Brooklyn and the Bronx (Box 6a, Folder 8)
  - Project Files - Contacts and Credits (Box 6a, Folder 9)
  - Project Files - Notes and Draft World Security Through International Resources Development by Hermann Herrey and Harlow Shapley (Box 6a, Folder 10)
  - Project Files - Notes and Draft World Security Through International Resources Development by Hermann Herrey and Harlow Shapley (Box 6a, Folder 11)
  - Working Files - Press (Box 6a, Folder 12)
  - Jacques Odersichfugen (Box 6a, Folder 13)
  - Project Files - A Project for an Institute of Planning by Hermann Herrey and John Bland (Box 6a, Folder 14)
  - Project Files - Draft Proposal International Institute for Resources Development (Box 6a, Folder 15)
  - Biographical Material (Box 6a, Folder 16)
- Architectural Portfolio (Box 6b)
  - Project Files - Misc. Correspondence (Box 6b, Folder 1)
  - Project Files - Chicken See Mir Reinen Dollar ("The Gimmick") (Box 6b, Folder 2)
  - Project Files - Bonn (Box 6b, Folder 3)
  - Project Files - Theatre including correspondence on design for Max Reinhardt (Box 6b, Folder 4)
  - Project Files - Notes and drafts of speech for American Philosophical Society (Box 6b, Folder 5)
  - Project Files - research grant proposal for the American Philosophical Society (Box 6b, Folder 6)
  - Project Files - research grant proposal for the American Philosophical Society (Box 6b, Folder 7)
  - McGill University (Box 6b, Folder 8)
  - Project Files - Notes and drafts for A Public Panel Discussion on International Resources Development at the Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace (Box 6b, Folder 9)
  - Project Files - Theatre (Box 6b, Folder 10)
  - Project Files - Theatre (Box 6b, Folder 11)
  - Project Files - Institute of Planning (Box 6b, Folder 12)
- Biographical information, 1 (Box 7)
- Folders mainly concerning his work on plays (some in German), 2 (Box 7)
- Folders relating to the American Philosophical Society, 3 (Box 7)
- Mss. copy and some typed copies of speech, November 1944, 4 (Box 7)
- Folders on International Resources Development (he seems to have been writing a book on this subject), 5 (Box 7)
- Folders on Institute of Planning, 6 (Box 7)
- Folders of correspondence with John Bland of McGill University, School of Architecture, 7 (Box 7)
- Workfile- About the Problem of the Future of Our Big Cities" American Academny of Arts annd Sciences, November 10th, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Workfile- Research and Correspondence re Lighting and Lamp Design, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Workfile - Chicago Urban Planning, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Workfile - House for Mr. & Mrs. Robert Mautner, Contract and Specs, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Workfile - City Planning Research and Notes, 1939-1944 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Workfile - Civic Theatre San Francisco, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Workfile - City Planning New York, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Workfile - Program for Research on Community Centers 1945 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Workfile - Eyre Estate, 20 Carlton Hill,, London UK, 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Workfile - Villa Court Garden Apartments, 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Workfile - Switlik Parachute Company, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Workfile - Planning Notes 1950 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Workfile - Patents for Chair design, 1933-1944 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Workfile - Patents Various, 1947-1944 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Workfile - Research, Lectures and Courses, 1939-1943 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Pen and Ink Drawing (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Workfile - Haupstadt Berlin, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Workfile - Nedick's Inc., 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Workfile - Nedick's Inc., 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Workfile - Nedick's Inc., 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Drawings and Notes 1940s (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Drawings and Notes 1940s (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Projects
  - Specifications and plans for specific jobs (Box 8)
  - Folders on Manhattan scheme (some in German); (We understand from his wife that most of the work in the N.Y. [Manhattan] scheme was done in his spare time) (Box 8)
  - Workfile - Metropolitan Planning, Manhattan Plan 1943 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Workfile - Metropolitan Planning Scheme for a Manhattan Interior Highway and Parking Belt (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Workfile Projects Facts about Manhattan1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Workfile - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Metropolitan Traffic 1943 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Workfile - Projects Metropolitan Planning (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Work File - Queens College Lectures, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Work File - Queens College Lectures, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Work File - Queens College Lectures The Family House, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Work File - Queens College Lectures The Family House, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Work File - Queens College Lectures The Family House, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Workfile - Modern Theatres, Factors and Trends typescript and handwritten manuscript drafts (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Workfile - Modern Theatres, Factors and Trends typescript and handwritten manuscript drafts (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Workfile - Correspondence Oswald Kolbert, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Work File - Correspondence 1943 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1940-1945 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1941-1945 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1942-1945 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Misc. Correspondence 1944 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Correspondence 1945 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1945-1951 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Letters of Introduction by and for Hermann Herrey, 1938-1951 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence War Manpower Commission 1943 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence Misc 1953 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Articles- Newspapers and Magazines
  - (Box 9)
- Photo Album, 1954-1960 (Box 10)
  Photographs from plays directed and designed by Hermann Herrey. Contains: "Jacques ou la Soumission", "Les Bonnes", "The Chairs", "Hedda Gabler", "Landschaft mit Figuren","Konig Nicolo", "Julius Caesar", "Macbeth", "The Taming of the Shrew"
- "Hauptstadt Berlin: Ergebnis des internationalen stadtebaulichen Ideenwettbewerbs", 1960 (Box 10)
- Blueprints of a Parking Garage (?) (Box 10)
- Architectural interest
  - Misc. correspondence, c. 1944 (Box Not 10)
  - Letters, etc,. of introduction, by H.H. and for H.H., 1938-1951 (Box Not 10)
  - Queen's College correspondence, c. 1944 (Box Not 10)
  - Correspondence re. projects, c. 1954-55 (Box Not 10)
  - Metropolitan Planning - Manhattan (Box Not 10)
  - Misc. plans (Box Not 10)
- NYT Magazine (Box Not 10)
- NYT (Box Not 10)
- Daily News (Box Not 10, Folder 1)
- Berliner Tageblatt (Box Not 10, Folder 2)
- Sudkurier (Box Not 10, Folder 3)
- New York Post (Box Not 10, Folder 4)
- The Architectural Review (Box Not 10, Folder 1)
- Die Dame (Box Not 10, Folder 2)
- The Architectural Review (Box Not 10, Folder 3)
- Illustrirte Zeitung (Box Not 10, Folder 4)
- Theatre interest
  - Folder relating to production of "King Nicolo" or "Such is Life" by Frank Wedekind (correspondence and script) (Box 11)
  - Correspondence publicity re. the above play (Box 11)
  - Drama Exchange Plan, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
  - Folder of correspondence concerning London theatres, also "On the Run" by Robert Vansittart, 1939-1940 (production deferred) (Box 11)
  - Note: "King Nicolo" as adapted, produced, and directed by H.H. (Box 11)
  - Many notes on the theatre (Box 11)
  - Diploma of German Critics Award to H.H., 1958-1959 (Box 11)
- "N" or "This is Our World" by Gilbert Tanner - Annotated Typewritten Scripts in English and German, ca. 1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Frank Wedekind's King Nicolo - Prompters Book 1955 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- "King Nicolo" or "Such is Life" by Frank Wedekind - Typewritten Script and Publicity 1955 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Workfile - OPUS Society for the Presentation of Works of Art "King Nicolo" Festival Production, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Workfile - OPUS Society for the Presentation of Works of Art "King Nicolo" Set Design, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Workfile - OPUS Society for the Presentation of Works of Art "King Nicolo" Correspondence and Notes, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Workfile - OPUS Society for the Presentation of Works of Art "King Nicolo" Rehersals, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Workfile - OPUS Society for the Presentation of Works of Art "King Nicolo"Correspondence, Publicity and Notes, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Theater - Research Notes and Correspondence 1940s (Box 11, Folder 9)
- "Abend und Morgen, Die Selbe Stadt" Schauspiel von August Strindberg Bearbeitet von Hermann Herrey (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Theater - Correspondence Dramaturgische Gesellschaft, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- "Gimmick" oder "Schicken sie mir Einen Dollar" von Joe Julian 1959 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Hermann Herrey - Ionescu und "Der Strom des Bewusstseins" (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Eugen Ionesco "Jacques oder Sich Fuegen" (Box 11, Folder 16)
- "Tugend in Gefahr" von Sir John Vanbrugh (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Theatre - Notes and Scripts, 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Theatre - Notes and Research, 1958-1960 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Theatre Sets, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Correspondence - Jack de Leon 1946 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Theatre - London Correspondence, Design Drawings and Notes, 1938-1940 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Theatre - Clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Theatre - Drawings (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Nine small boxes of glass negatives of furniture and other subjects, 1 (Box 12)
- Die Bauberatung, January 1, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Das Schonste, 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Das Schonste, 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Talks, Reports, etc. by H.H.
  - Address to the City Club of New York Committee on Streets and Traffic Luncheon, Jan. 22, 1971, 1 (Box 13)